A Guide to the Joyce Oron Architectural Collection, 1985-2004
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Joyce Oron Architectural Collection, 1985-2004.
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms2005-006
23.3 cu. ft. 1 flat box; 13 tube boxes; 17 oversize folders
Joyce Oron's architecture and town planning office is located in Israel. This collection contains drawings, text, and photographs of some of the prestigious projects handled by her office from 1985 to 2004. Most materials are written in Hebrew with English descriptions available.
Oron, Joyce, 1954-
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The creator donated the Joyce Oron material to the International Archive of Women in Architecture in October 2004. Additional material was donated in 2009.
Biographical/Historical Information
Joyce Oron was born in 1954 in New York, and lived in the United States and Uruguay until she was 18 years old. In 1972, political circumstances drove her to Israel, where she completed her schooling and graduated as an architect from the Faculty of Architecture at Technion, Haifa in 1978.
From 1978 to 1985 she worked in the office of Lofenfeld–Gamerman, where she became a partner. In 1985, she set up her own office, Joyce Oron Architecture and Town Planner, which she expanded in 1994. During 1985 to 1987, Oron was the main architect of the town Beit Berl. Joyce Oron's office has worked on such varied projects as public buildings, housing projects, urban planning, community centers, health facilities, schools, sports halls and facilities, office buildings and neighborhoods. Her work has been featured in several magazines, and her office has won many design competitions.
Oron is a consulting architect for the Ministry on Education for the development of schools and is also active in the development of neighborhoods for soldiers and their families for the Ministry of Defense. Since the mid 1990s, she has been giving guest lectures at the Faculty of Architecture at Technion and the Faculty of Architecture in the University of Tel Aviv.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of architectural drawings, photographs and textual description of projects created by Joyce Oron from 1985 to 2004. There are a wide variety of projects in the collection, including residential, commercial and institutional buildings in Israel. Most drawings are 36 inches wide, vary in length from 48 to 96 inches, and include text only in Hebrew. Most projects also have a brief English description along with photographs of the completed building. The project drawings are complemented by a recording of a lecture by Joyce Oron at the 14th Congress of UIFA (Union internationale des femmes architectes) in September 2004 and two issues of the magazine "Architecture in Israel" that feature Oron's work.
Arrangement
The collection is described in two series: Professional Papers and Project records. The drawings in the collection are grouped by project and stored by size. Projects with long drawing sheets are stored rolled in tube boxes. Other project drawings are stored flat in oversized folders. Box 1 contains a spiral–bound set of drawings for one of the projects, a CD with the UIFA lecture and a rolled set of architectural drawing sheets. File folders with photographs and textual information in English about most projects, as well as two magazines, are stored in a small document box (Box 1a) inside Box 1.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
For more information about architect Joyce Oron and the work undertaken by her office refer to her official website, www.joyceoron.com.
The IAWA collection UIFA 14th Congress Materials contains a poster that Oron presented at the conference. Ms2005-011
Index Terms
Persons:
Oron, Joyce, 1954-
Occupations:
Architects.
Genres:
Architectural drawings.
Local Subjects:
International Archive of Women in Architecture (IAWA)
Subjects:
Women-owned architectural firms.
Contents List
- Professional Papers.
  - Résumé. (Box-folder 1-1)
  - Biography, 1954-2005. (Box-folder 1a-1)
  - Compiled Booklet, Professional Work, 1985-2004. (Box-folder 1a-2)
  - Lecture on CD, Is There A Feminine Architecture, 3 copies. (Box-folder 1-4)
  - Promotional CDs for Joyce Oron Architecture and Town Planning (8 CDs). (Box-folder 1-5)
  - Magazine, "Architecture in Israel.". (Box-folder 1a-18)
    - December 1998 (Box-folder 1a-18)
    - December 2000 (Box-folder 1a-18)
- Project Records.
  - Community Center, Merhavim Regional Council.
    - Drawings and Text. (Box-folder 1-3)
  - Modiin, Natural Reserves, Modiin.
    - Project Information and Photographs. (Box-folder 1a-3)
    - Architectural Drawings (16 sheets). (Box 2)
  - Cluster of Cottages, Holon.
    - Project Information and Photographs. (Box-folder 1a-4)
    - Architectural Drawings (10 sheets). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 1)
  - Cluster of Cottages, Beer Sheva.
    - Project Information and Photographs. (Box-folder 1a-5)
    - Architectural Drawings (8 sheets). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 14)
  - Beit Eliezer Community Center, Hadera.
    - Project Information and Photographs. (Box-folder 1a-6)
    - Architectural Drawings (21 sheets). (Box 3)
  - Community Center, Savyon.
    - Project Information and Photographs. (Box-folder 1a-7)
  - Center for Family Health, Modiin.
    - Project Information and Photographs. (Box-folder 1a-8)
    - Architectural Drawings (6 sheets). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 6)
  - Gaby Mode – Botelho Wizo Center, Givatayim.
    - Project Information and Photographs. (Box-folder 1a-9)
    - Architectural Drawings (20 sheets). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 4)
  - Givat Shmuel Kindergartens.
    - Project Information and Photographs. (Box-folder 1a-10)
    - Architectural Drawings (7 sheets). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 3)
  - Bnei Akiva Preparatorial School, Laboratory Building, Givat Shmuel.
    - Project Information and Photographs. (Box-folder 1a-11)
    - Architectural Drawings (10 sheets). (Box 4)
  - Netivei Noam High School, Gedera.
    - Project Information and Photographs. (Box-folder 1a-12)
    - Architectural Drawings (10 sheets). (Box 5)
  - Tullerie Gardens, Ganei Tikva.
    - Project Information and Photographs. (Box-folder 1a-13)
    - Architectural Drawings (32 sheets). (Box-folder 1-2)
  - Eial Shimoni Sports Center.
    - Project Information and Photographs. (Box-folder 1a-14)
  - City Square, Qiryat Ono.
    - Project Information and Photographs. (Box-folder 1a-15)
    - Architectural Drawings (7 sheets). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 3)
  - Central Library, Haifa.
    - Project Information and Photographs. (Box-folder 1a-16)
  - Labour Council Building, Ashkelon.
    - Project Information and Scanned Images. (Box-folder 1a-17)
  - Community Center of Madoim, Merhavim.
    - Project Information and Scanned Images. (Box-folder 1a-17)
  - Brainen Rueben Kindergarten, Geha Hospital.
    - Project Information and Scanned Images. (Box-folder 1a-17)
    - Architectural Drawings (55 sheets). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 5)
  - Rubin Recreation Center, Yerocham.
    - Architectural Drawings (21 sheets). (Box 6)
  - Milton School Wind Addition, Bat-Yam.
    - Architectural Drawings (6 sheets). (Box 7)
  - Meirev and Amos Residence.
    - Architectural Drawings (8 sheets). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 7)
  - Kid's Bedroom, Tel Aviv.
    - Architectural Drawings (10 sheets). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 7)
  - Dorothy and Buno Markus Apartment, Herzlia.
    - Architectural Drawings (11 sheets). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 7)
  - 31 Cottages, Beiter Ilit.
    - Architectural Drawings (5 sheets). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 7)
  - Neighborhood B South, Ariel.
    - Architectural Drawings (20 sheets). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 8)
  - Mall Herzelia.
    - Architectural Drawings (9 sheets). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 9)
  - Telephone Table.
    - Architectural Drawings (1 sheet). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 9)
  - Parents Bathroom Renovation.
    - Architectural Drawings (10 sheets). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 10)
  - The Sznajder's Residence.
    - Architectural Drawings (5 sheets). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 10)
  - Isreal Jewish Agency, Idud Bank.
    - Architectural Drawings (3 sheets). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 10)
  - Pisgat Shlomi Project, Beer Sheva.
    - Architectural Drawings (2 sheets). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 10)
  - The Wolfson Community Center, Holon.
    - Architectural Drawings (1 sheet). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/ Folder 11)
  - Tamar Goldberg Bathroom.
    - Architectural Drawings (1 sheet). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/ Folder 11)
  - Mira and Ofer Berger Apartment, Ramat Aviv.
    - Architectural Drawings (1 sheet). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/ Folder 11)
  - Senat Building in the University of Tel Aviv.
    - Architectual Drawings (2 sheets). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 11)
  - The Central Theater of Beer Sheva.
    - Architectural Drawings (2 sheets). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 11)
  - Senior Citizen Community Center in Givat Olga.
    - Architectural Drawings (4 drawings). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 12)
  - Tzofit's Theater.
    - Architectural Drawings (6 sheets). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 12)
  - Donner's Home-Daniel Hotel.
    - Architectural Drawings (15 sheets). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 13)
  - Mother-In-Law Kitchen Renovation.
    - Architectural Drawings (2 sheets). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 13)
  - Ben Gurion School, Ramle.
    - Architectural Drawings (9 sheets). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 14)
  - Ramot Hefer School, Emek Hefer.
    - Architectural Drawings (9 sheets). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 15)
  - Center Landscaping Offices, Rehovot.
    - Architectural Drawings (2 sheets). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 15)
    - The Broinen Reuben Kindergarten in Geha Hospital, Petach Tikva.
      - Architectural Drawings (17 sheets). (Box 9)
  - Ami Shinar Apartment, Tel Aviv.
    - Architectural Drawings (2 sheets). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 15)
  - South Triangle Neighborhood, Civil Park, Petach Tikva.
    - Architectural Drawings (11 sheets). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 16)
  - Sports Hall for the Givat Michael School, Nes Ziona.
    - Architectural Drawings (7 sheets). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 16)
  - Shoham Zoo.
    - Architectural Drawings (5 sheets). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 16)
  - Sports Hall, Reene.
    - Architectural Drawings (2 sheets). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 16)
  - Happy New Year, 1999-2000.
    - Promotional Material (2 materials). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 17)
  - Picture Collage of Morocco, 1998.
    - Collage (1 poster). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 17)
  - Architects Paint Bauhaus, 2004.
    - Poster (1 double sided poster). (Oversize Map-case 9/Drawer 2/Folder 17)
  - Specialized School and Hospital.
    - Architectural Drawings (9 sheets). (Box 8)
    - The Steinburg Community Center Restoration.
      - Architectual Drawings (4 sheets). (Box 10)
  - Gibshtein Project, Rishon Lezion.
    - Architectural Drawings (10 sheets). (Box 11)
  - The Uri Elian Theater.
    - Architectural Drawings (13 sheets). (Box 12)
  - David Hamelech Apartment, Tel Aviv.
    - Architectural Drawings (12 sheets). (Box 13)